CHRISTOPHER W. LEHMAN

github: thecwlzone http://www.linkedin.com/in/christopherwlehman

www.thecwlzone.com

SUMMARY

4+ years as a Software Developer with a history of successful delivery of RESTful web applications. 3+ years experience with Ruby and Rails and the Open Source community. Experienced with the entire Ruby on Rails stack coupled with a strong foundation in Object Oriented programming and practices. 4+ years of standards compliant HTML, XHTML, CSS and JavaScript experience. Always motivated to implement new technologies and software; eager to contribute vision in a creative and fast paced environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Ruby on Rails
- OOP / Design Patterns
- LAMP + Ruby, Perl
- jQuery / Prototype
- Apache / Passenger / Nginx
- Webgen / Haml / SASS
- MySQL / MS SQL Server
- Git / SVN / Capistrano
- Rspec / Cucumber

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PROFITSTREAMS, LLC, Denver, Colorado

Senior Software Developer

2010 – Present

- Senior member of the ProfitStreams Ruby on Rails team that has taken the RevenuePWR application through four major releases since November 2010. Core technologies include Rails 2.3.5, Capistrano / Bamboo deployment, Apache and Nginx web servers, Git and GiHub version control and JIRA bug tracking system. Code releases are coordinated via Agile one and two week sprints.
- Team lead for the integration of the Profitstreams Online Ordering application. Successful milestones include launch of the original code base, migration of the code from Rails 1.2.6 to Rails 2.3.5, and integration of the OO user roles, permissions and administrative functionalities into the RevenuePWR database. Currently developing API architectures between OO and revenuePWR using ActiveMQ, SparkBase and Java technologies.

INTERNETPAWN.COM, INCORPORATED, Centennial, Colorado

2010

Software Developer

Principal **Ruby on Rails** Web Developer for www.boomeranglending.com, www.internetpawn.com and www.prestamista.com - the company is now rebranded as Pawngo at www.pawngo.com

- Responsible for the integration of custom landing pages and targeted marketing campaigns into the Refinery CMS Rails-based framework.
- Management of Search Engine Optimization, marketing keyword identification and extraction, and backend reporting systems.
- Oversight of backend capabilities including enhancements of admin and customer support functions and database backups.
- Support and maintenance of corporate IT assets (MS Outlook / Exchange, Windows 2003 Server, hosted web site performance).

BOECORE, INCORPORATED, Colorado Springs, Colorado *Software Developer*

2009 - 2010

Team member for software development of the Bilateral Certification and Accreditation Tool (BoBCAT), a **Ruby on Rails** high-traffic file storage, retrieval, tagging and reporting system.

• Developed unit and functional tests for the code base. Defined and created use case documentation. Detected and repaired bugs, integrated code changes into the Unfuddle ticket system and the Git version control system.

- Tested BoBCAT GUI using Watir and Selenium. Tested CSS layouts and AJAX forms against the major browsers including IE 6. Verified Redbox and Paperclip plugins against the client's file system and browser environments.
- Provided on-site customer interface between the development team and end users. Worked directly with end users to refine requirements.
- Created and managed documentation deliverables including MS Project schedule, Work Breakdown Structure,
 Project Management Plan, Configuration Management procedures, Risk Analysis and Test Plan.
- Delivered the product to the customer 30 days ahead of schedule.

INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS MACHINES, Colorado Springs, Colorado

2005 - 2009

- Senior Engineer
- Improved productivity by developing Ruby on Rails web sites to monitor batch job submissions, and to track bug reports and feature requests.
- Designed, tested and evaluated file system performance by creating Perl code to simulate disk I/O operations.
- Reduced productivity losses by developing Ruby on Rails web sites to monitor disk space quotas for projects and designers and to monitor tool license usage.
- Enhanced productivity of circuit design methodology by developing Perl and Ruby scripting tools

Software Engineer

- Team member for C++ software development of algorithms for use in the Clock Planning Router tool.
- Refactored code for CPR routing estimation algorithms.

CYPRESS SEMICONDUCTOR, Colorado Springs, Colorado

2000 - 2005

Software Engineer

- Yielded a \$3.2 million savings by developing a Ruby on Rails web site to filter and graphically display hardware resource utilization metrics.
- Created HTML-based web sites and Wikis to support documentation for design groups.
- Developed various Perl and Ruby scripts to streamline the circuit design process flow.

EDUCATION

MSCS, Colorado Technical University, Colorado Springs, Colorado BSEE, Northeastern University, Boston, Massachusetts Certification: PMI Fundamentals of Project Management

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Member, Denver DeRailed User Group Member, Colorado Springs Open Source Software Group Member, Not Just Ruby Users Group Member, Pikes Peak Linux Users Group